<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collections on Quire Starter</title>
    <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collections on Quire Starter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Collections/Artists’ Oeuvres</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takis and the Fourth Dimension</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/7-stephenson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/7-stephenson/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Takis is known for his investigations into the relationship between art and science. His earliest works include bronze forms focused on concepts of force and volume. Later he began his ongoing Signaux series with the development of wind-activated antenna-like structures inspired by radio and radar apparatuses. In the late 1950s he began including magnetism in his paintings and sculptures, employing electromagnets to fix objects in space, generate motion, and elicit sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Performativity</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/8-pavic_mestric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/8-pavic_mestric/</guid>
      <description>Srnec and His Luminoplastics Figure 8.1.  Aleksandar Srnec, Space Modulator, 1953, colored wires, wood, 49.5 × 53.6 × 18 cm. Modern Gallery, Zagreb.   Aleksandar Srnec (Zagreb, 1924–2010) was a prominent Croatian artist whose work developed between 1950 and 1970, a vital period for the arts as well as for international culture, politics, and economics. Srnec was a member of the EXAT 51 group, active in the early 1950s, which sought to introduce experimentation into art and based its activities on the theories and traditions of Russian Constructivism, Bauhaus, and Neoplasticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering a Solution</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/9-gillies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/9-gillies/</guid>
      <description>The Latin American department at the Museum of Fine Arts, Houston (MFAH), began collecting kinetic art in 2004, including works by pioneering artists of the 1960s such as Abraham Palatnik, Horacio García Rossi, Gyula Kosice, Gregorio Vardanega, Martha Boto, and Julio Le Parc. They used various mechanisms—mirrors, the interplay of lights, and bubbling water—to produce movement and create both regular and random patterns. These artworks were displayed in multiple exhibitions, which provided challenges in maintaining their functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intertwined Strategies for Conservation and Display of Kinetic Art</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/10-pola_ferriani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/10-pola_ferriani/</guid>
      <description>Behavioral Kinetics  Figure 10.1.  Giacomo Balla’s Bambina che corre sul balcone (Girl running on a balcony), 1912.   Figure 10.2.  Gianni Colombo walking through his environment Topoestesia (Tre zone contigue—Itinerario programmato) (Topoesthesia [Three contiguous zones—Programmed itinerary]), 1965–70, Palazzo delle Esposizioni, Rome, 1970.   Giacomo Balla’s Bambina che corre sul balcone (Girl running on a balcony), from 1912, is in the collection of the Galleria d’Arte Moderna in Milan and is currently undergoing restoration in Ferriani’s studio (fig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Examination and Conservation of Thirteen Artworks by Jean Tinguely in the Collection of the Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/11-meijer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/collections/11-meijer/</guid>
      <description>Tinguely and the Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam The Stedelijk Museum holds thirteen three-dimensional kinetic works by Jean Tinguely (1925–1991). Created between 1954 and 1971, they provide a clear view of Tinguely’s development as an artist. The earliest work in the collection is Elément détaché III (1954), a very fragile “thread relief,” and the latest is the heavy machine Méta II (1971).
Former Stedelijk director Willem Sandberg and former curator Ad Petersen befriended Tinguely in the 1960s, and they started collecting his work for the museum after the Stedelijk’s exhibitions Bewogen Beweging (Moving movement) (1961) and Dylaby (1962) (Schavemaker, Til, and Wismer 2016:155–61).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>