<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posters on Quire Starter</title>
    <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posters on Quire Starter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conserving Mechanical Elements in Technological Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/16-cappellina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/16-cappellina/</guid>
      <description>Cockcroft-Walton Generator First designed in 1932, the Cockcroft–Walton generator is an electric circuit that produces a high voltage from a low voltage. A system of capacitors and diodes generates this voltage, along with kinetic components such as dynamos (fig. 16.1), which are housed inside rounded aluminum protections. The machine is assembled over two Bakelite isolating cylinders. The electrical components were lost during the first installation in the museum in the 1960s; furthermore, safety concerns prevent us from activating the machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Big!</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/17-erhan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/17-erhan/</guid>
      <description>Artwork and Art History  Figure 17.1a.  Jonathan Borofsky’s Ballerina Clown, 1990, installed in the courtyard of the Museum Ludwig Forum Aachen.   Figure 17.1b.  The mechanism that moves the leg of Jonathan Borofsky’s Ballerina Clown, 1990.   Ballerina Clown (1990) by Jonathan Borofsky (b. 1942) is composed of a female ballerina body wearing a male clown mask. This “transvestite figure (half clown, half ballerina)” (Citation: Ottinger 2004, 39[Ottinger, Didier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conserving a Kinetic “Rotor”</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/18-iazurlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/18-iazurlo/</guid>
      <description>During the second half of the 1950s, artist Heinz Mack (b. 1931) developed his interest in lighting and kinetic phenomena with his Rotors. This series of works is laminated with shiny metal and creates moving light reflections via movement produced by a small motor housed on the back. Light Dynamo belongs to this phase of the artist’s production; it was recently identified as a work realized by Mack in 1960 for the ZERO group’s only exhibition in Rome: Mack + Klein + Piene + Uecker + Lo Savio = 0, of 1961.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering the Continuum of Care for Outdoor Kinetic Sculpture</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/19-mack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/19-mack/</guid>
      <description>Meteorological science has documented that climate change has resulted in more storms and increasing storm intensity over recent decades (Citation: Melillo, Richmond, and Yohe 2014[Melillo, Jerry M., Terese (T. C.) Richmond, and Gary W. Yohe, eds. 2014. Climate Change Impacts in the United States: The Third National Climate Assessment. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Global Change Research Program. doi:10.7930/J0Z31WJ2.]). These new weather-related challenges necessitate that new display protocols for outdoor sculpture be adopted by the field, just as recommendations for indoor museum environments were standardized in 1978 with the publication of Garry Thomson’s Museum Environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gianni Colombo’s *Strutturazione cinevisuale abitabile*</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/20-peller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/20-peller/</guid>
      <description>Gianni Colombo’s Strutturazione cinevisuale abitabile Strutturazione cinevisuale abitabile (Inhabitable cinevisual structure) from 1964, a light environment by Milanese artist Gianni Colombo (1937–1993), is composed of two perpendicular square panels1 fixed to a wall (fig. 20.1). The artwork is meant to be shown in a small, darkened room, with the spectator stepping into the space outlined by the lights. Short and intermittent bursts of light flash simultaneously on each panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;em&gt;Death of a moment&lt;/em&gt;</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/21-stamatopoulou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/21-stamatopoulou/</guid>
      <description>Born in Zurich, Urs Fischer (b. 1973) is a prominent contemporary artist who uses a wide variety of media and materials to create assemblages, paintings, digital montages, spatial installations, kinetic objects, and texts. Death of a moment (2007) is a site-specific installation consisting of a wall (13.5 × 3.2m) mounted with floor-to-ceiling mirrors (fig. 21.1). The mirrors perform a regular, barely noticeable tilting motion, which creates a disturbing effect on spatial perception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future in Motion</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/22-van_aubel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/22-van_aubel/</guid>
      <description>Dutch artist Ray Staakman (b. 1941) was a pioneer in kinetic art in the Netherlands during the 1960s and 1970s, and the movement in his artworks creates intriguing optical effects by the displacement of shapes. Unfortunately, several of his works began to malfunction after repeated use and could no longer be displayed. In 2012, the University of Amsterdam (UvA), in collaboration with the Rijksdienst voor het Cultureel Erfgoed (RCE; the Cultural Heritage Agency, Netherlands), began a major conservation project of seven of Staakman’s early kinetic artworks in the collection of the RCE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conservation Ethics of and Strategies for Preserving and Exhibiting an Operational Car</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/23-van_mourik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/posters/23-van_mourik/</guid>
      <description>The Artwork Figure 23.1.  Joost Conijn’s Hout Auto (Wood Car) in the garden of the Centraal Museum. Centraal Museum Utrecht.   In 2001 artist Joost Conijn (b. 1971) created Wood Car (fig. 23.1) from the base of a Citroën DS, building the coach from plywood and installing a wood-burning apparatus that powered the engine instead of gas. In 2002 the artist drove Wood Car through fifteen countries in Europe, collecting wood along the way and documenting his journey on video.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>