<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keynotes on Quire Starter</title>
    <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keynotes on Quire Starter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynotes</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Question of KinEthics</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/1-bek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/1-bek/</guid>
      <description>When the intention of a kinetic artwork is its movement, is it still a kinetic artwork when it does not move? Do we “keep it moving” even when motion is detrimental to its existence? The challenge associated with the preservation of kinetic artwork is encapsulated in this simple conundrum: Is retirement from movement an appropriate method of preservation for an artwork meant to move?
As first-generation kinetic and Op Art from the 1960s grow older, they are acquiring a historical status due to the obsolescence of light bulbs, electric timers, and motor controls: art professionals can no longer simply replace parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fluid Boundaries between Interpretation and Overinterpretation</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/2-caianiello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/keynotes/2-caianiello/</guid>
      <description>Interpretation and Overinterpretation All professionals engaged with the conservation and restoration of kinetic objects are familiar with this tool: the screwdriver. This paper is about the use of a screwdriver; however, it does not explain how to use it to open a case and repair a motor. Rather, it employs it as a metaphor to explore the boundaries between interpretation and overinterpretation.
In 1962, Italian semiotician Umberto Eco published his Opera aperta (The Open Work) in which he theorizes about the category of “open works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>