<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Case-studies on Quire Starter</title>
    <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Case-studies on Quire Starter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and Furious</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/3-gilberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/3-gilberg/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Figure 3.1.  Chris Burden’s Metropolis II in action.   Artist Chris Burden (1946–2015) designed and fabricated Metropolis II (2011), an intense kinetic sculpture modeled after a frenetic modern city (fig. 3.1). Steel tubing (Unistrut®) forms a structural grid interwoven with an elaborate system of eighteen roadways, including a six-lane freeway, and HO-scale1 train tracks. Miniature cars speed through the city at 240 scale miles per hour; every hour, the equivalent of approximately one hundred thousand cars circulates through the sculpture’s dense network of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conserving Thomas Wilfred’s *Lumia Suite, Opus 158*</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/4-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/4-snow/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Wilfred: The Unrecognized Pioneer Thomas Wilfred (1889–1968) was born Richard Edgar Løvstrøm in Naestved on the island of Zealand, Denmark. In Copenhagen, as a precocious sixteen year old, he began experimenting with light as an artistic medium, using a cigar box, incandescent light, and colored glass to create colored projections. Later, when he studied painting at the Sorbonne, he expanded his setup to several cardboard boxes, lenses, and a bedsheet screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybernetic *Umbrella*</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/5-lawson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/5-lawson/</guid>
      <description>The Context of Kinetic Art Conservation at Tate Tate acquired its first kinetic work in 1951 (Lynn Chadwick’s Dragonfly), and there are now approximately sixty kinetic sculptures in the collection, including mobiles, interactive works, and motorized works. Each artwork has its own complexities relating to display; therefore, conservation needs are reviewed on an individual basis and require a variety of implementation approaches. The following three sculptures highlight some, but not all, of the different approaches that could be applied to Tsai’s Umbrella, based on previous work within Tate conservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving with the Times</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/6-phillips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/case-studies/6-phillips/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Without loan requests, some of the most fascinating and challenging conservation projects would end up languishing on to-do lists. Complex projects tend to be event-driven rather than the result of strategic long-term planning (Citation: Smithsonian Institution 2010[Smithsonian Institution. 2010. Collaborations in Conserving Time-Based Art: A Summary of Discussion Group Sessions of a Colloquium Co-organized by the Lunder Conservation Center of the Smithsonian American Art Museum and National Portrait Gallery and the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>