<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theoretical-issues on Quire Starter</title>
    <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theoretical-issues on Quire Starter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Issues</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hype about ZERO and Its Influence on the Conservation and Presentation of Early Kinetic Works</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/12-heydenreich_giebeler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/12-heydenreich_giebeler/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In 1958, in search of a new artistic beginning—a Stunde Null, or “zero hour”—Otto Piene (1928–2014) and Heinz Mack (b. 1931) founded the artist magazine ZERO, which was later to give its name to an international art movement. In 1961, Günther Uecker (b. 1930) began to collaborate closely with Piene and Mack. They quickly gained considerable popularity through their light-kinetics, and they initiated numerous projects that involved other artists such as Jean Tinguely, Lucio Fontana, and Yves Klein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Multiples</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/13-plante/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/13-plante/</guid>
      <description>Figure 13.1.  Julio Le Parc. Catalogue of the XXXIII Biennale di Venezia, Italia, 1966. Cover designer Rogelio Polesello overprinted a plot of colors on the black-and-white photograph of Le Parc’s kinetic multiple. Museo Nacional de Bellas Artes, Buenos Aires.   In 1966, Julio Le Parc represented Argentina in the Venice Biennale (fig. 13.1) and received the international grand prize in painting. According to the reviews, his space was one of the most visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collection of Nicolas Schöffer</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/14-dhaenens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/14-dhaenens/</guid>
      <description>Into the Artist’s Studio: From Kinetic to Cybernetic  Figure 14.1.  View of Nicolas Schöffer’s studio in the Villa des Arts, Paris.   Figure 14.2a.  Spatiodynamism Spationynamique 16 with Maurice Béjart, 1953.   Figure 14.2b.  Luminodynamism Lux 2, 1957.   With more than six hundred objects, the collection of Nicolas Schöffer (1912–1992) is nearly complete. Currently installed in his Paris studio, it contains most of his unique artworks and at least one work from each of his series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Pretty Good for the 21st Century”</title>
      <link>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/15-brobbel_rees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gettypubs.github.io/quire-starter/theoretical-issues/15-brobbel_rees/</guid>
      <description>Figure 15.1.  Len Lye with Flip, ca. 1975.   The New Zealand–born Len Lye (1901–1980) remains one of the most enigmatic of modernist artists. Leaving his homeland in his mid-twenties to seek out less provincial pastures, Lye traveled between Australia and Samoa, becoming familiar with aboriginal and Pacific cultures before arriving in London in 1926, where he was immediately welcomed by the British avant-garde. Several years exhibiting sculpture, painting, and photography with the Seven and Five Society,1 followed by an off-kilter relationship with the British Surrealists, are secondary to his career at the vanguard of experimental cinema.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>